Guide to the Byron D. Sher Papers
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Byron D. Sher papers
1949-1990s
SC1119
Sher, Byron D.
18 Linear feet
18 linear feet (12 boxes)
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Information about Access
The materials are open for research use. Audio-visual materials are not available in original format, and must be reformatted to a digital use copy.
Biographical/Historical note
Byron D. Sher was born February 7, 1928, in St. Louis, Missouri. Sher is an American Democratic politician who served in the California State Senate from 1996 to 2004, and in the California State Assembly between 1980 and 1996. He received his BA from Washington University in St. Louis and his JD from Harvard Law School. Before beginning his political career, Sher taught at several schools, including Harvard Law School, Southern Methodist University, and was a longtime professor at Stanford Law School.
Text excerpted from: http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Byron_Sher
Scope and Contents
Collection contains mostly teaching files from Sher's time at Harvard Law School, Southern Methodist University, and Stanford Law School. Other miscellaneous files include correspondence, resumes and CVs, and some books belonging to Sher.
Arrangement
Materials are arranged into four series: Harvard Law School; Southern Methodist University; Stanford Law School; and Miscellaneous.
Access Terms
Stanford University. School of Law.; Law--Study and teaching.
Collection Contents
- Records, Accession 2005-366
  - Harvard Law School
    - HLS notes - Contracts (notebook 1), 1949 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - HLS notes - Contracts (notebook 2), 1950 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - HLS notes - Criminal Law, 1949 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - HLS notes - Procedure (notebook 1), 1949 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - HLS notes - Procedure (notebook 2), 1949 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - HLS notes - Property I (notebook 1), 1949 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - HLS notes - Property I (notebook 2), 1950 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - HLS notes - Torts (notebook 1), 1949 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - HLS notes - Torts (notebook 2), 1950 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - HLS notes - Accounting, 1950 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - HLS notes - Agency, 1950 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - HLS notes - Constitutional Law (notebook 1), 1950 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - HLS notes - Constitutional Law (notebook 2), 1951 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - HLS notes - Corporations I (notebook 1), 1950 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - HLS notes - Corporations I (notebook 2, 1950 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - HLS notes - Legislation, 1950 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - HLS notes - Property II (notebook 1), 1950 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - HLS notes - Property II (notebook 2, 1951 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - HLS notes - Taxation (notebook 1), 1950 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - HLS notes - Taxation (notebook 2), 1951 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - HLS notes - Trusts (notebook 1), 1950 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - HLS notes - Trusts (notebook 2), 1951 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - HLS notes - Administrative Law, 1951 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - HLS notes - Conflicts of Laws, 1951 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - HLS notes - Evidence, 1951 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - HLS notes - Investment Management, 1951 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - HLS notes - Restitution, 1951 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - HLS notes - Corporations II (notebook 1), 1951 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - HLS notes - Corporations II (notebook 2), 1951 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - HLS notes - Commercial Law (notebook 1), 1951 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - HLS notes - Commercial Law (notebook 2, 1952 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - HLS notes - Current Tax Problems, 1952 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - HLS notes - Seminar in Problems in Taxation, 1952 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - HLS Yearbook, 1950 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - HLS Yearbook, 1951 (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - HLS Class of 1952 - 10th Year Report, 1962 (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - HLS Class of 1952 - 25th Year Report, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - HLS Class of 1952 - 30th Year Report, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Massachusetts Bar Exam, 1952 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Southern Methodist University
    - SMU course - Legal Accounting, 1950s (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - SMU course - Legal Accounting, 1956 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - SMU course - Insurance (binder 1), 1955 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - SMU course - Insurance (binder 2), 1955 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - SMU course - Legal Writing, 1955-1957 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - SMU course - Torts I, 1956 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - SMU course - Business Associations - Agency, 1950s (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - SMU course - Business Associations II - Corporations (binder 1), 1956 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - SMU course - Business Associations II - Corporations (binder 2), 1956 (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - SMU course - Business Associations II - Corporations, 1957 (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - SMU course - Security in Promised Advantages - Academy of American Law, 1957 (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - SMU course - Partnerships Texas Law, 1957 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Stanford Law School
    - SLS course - Commercial Law I - Bills and Notes, 1950s (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - SLS course - Commercial Law I - Sale of Goods, 1950s (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - SLS course - Commercial Law II - Sale of Goods, 1957 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - SLS course - Law in Society (taught by Harold Shepherd), 1959 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - SLS course - Commercial Law I - Sale of Goods, 1960s (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - SLS course - Contracts, 1960s (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - SLS course - Contracts, 1960s (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - SLS course - Contracts, 1960s (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - SLS course - Contracts, 1960s (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - SLS course - Contracts (binder 1), 1964 (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - SLS course - Contracts (binder 2), 1964 (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - SLS course - Creditors' Rights, 1963 (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - SLS course - Creditors' Rights (binder 1), 1967 (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - SLS course - Creditors' Rights (binder 2), 1967 (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - SLS course - Creditors' Rights (binder 3), 1967 (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - SLS course - Contracts (binder 1), 1969 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - SLS course - Contracts (binder 2), 1969 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - SLS course - Contracts (binder 3), 1969 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - SLS course - Contracts (binder 4), 1969 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - SLS course - Bar Exam (for Contracts), 1971 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - SLS course - Sales and Sales Financing (binder 1), 1971 (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - SLS course - Sales and Sales Financing (binder 2), 1971 (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - SLS course - Sales and Sales Financing (binder 3), 1971 (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - SLS course - Sales and Sales Financing (binder 4), 1971 (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - SLS course - Commercial and Consumer Transactions, 1975 (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - SLS course - Commercial and Consumer Transactions, 1977 (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - SLS course - Debtor/Creditor Relations (taught by Treister), 1977 (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - SLS course - Intro to Statutory Analysis - Consumer Transactions, part 1, 1979 (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - SLS course - Intro to Statutory Analysis - Consumer Transactions, part 2, 1979 (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - SLS course - Intro to Statutory Analysis - Consumer Transactions, part 3, 1979 (Box 6, Folder 15)
    - SLS course - Intro to Statutory Analysis - Assignments 1-6, 1979 (Box 6, Folder 16)
    - SLS course - Intro to Statutory Analysis - Assignments 7-13, 1979 (Box 6, Folder 17)
    - SLS course - Commercial Law - Secured Transactions (Box 6, Folder 18)
    - Contracts: Old Files #1 (Contracts is a course Sher taught for many years), 1970s-1980s (Box 7)
    - Contracts: Old Files #2 (Contracts is a course Sher taught for many years), 1960s-1970s (Box 8)
    - Contracts and Legislation (seminar), 1980s-1990s (Box 9)
    - Consumer Protection; Commercial Law; Commercial and Consumer Transactions; Three spiral notebooks from the Economic Institute for Law Professors (at George Mason University School of Law?), 1974-1980s (Box 10)
  - Miscellaneous
    - Correspondence; Sher's publications (random selection); Sher's resumes and CVs; Other Miscellaneous, 1958-1990s (Box 11)
    - Miscellaneous, including Sher's books (Box 12)